<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://qiriro.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://qiriro.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-12-15T10:04:26+00:00</updated><id>https://qiriro.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">CFP -AFRETEC seed grants</title><link href="https://qiriro.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CFP -AFRETEC seed grants"/><published>2023-12-14T20:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qiriro.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links%202</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qiriro.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links-2/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction-and-background">Introduction and Background</h1> <p>I’m thrilled to share an exciting new <a href="https://qiriro.github.io/assets/pdf/grants/afretec-seed-grant - 2024-CFP.pdf">research funding opportunity</a>from the African Engineering and Technology Network (Afretec) focused on driving inclusive digital transformation across Africa.</p> <p>Afretec, an initiative spearheaded by Carnegie Mellon University Africa, just announced a call for proposals for collaborative seed grants up to $50,000 to support pioneering research related to digital technologies.</p> <h1 id="eligibility-criteria">Eligibility Criteria</h1> <ul> <li> <p>Applicant teams must consist of Principal Investigator (PI) researchers from at least two Afretec member universities namely The American University in Cairo, Carnegie Mellon University, University of Lagos, University of Nairobi, University of Rwanda and the University of Witwatersrand.</p> </li> <li> <p>Additional PIs from non-Afretec African universities are eligible to be part of the application team and receive funding under this seed grant. Additional institutions that are not African universities can be engaged but cannot receive any resources through the seed grant.</p> </li> <li> <p>A researcher can serve as a lead PI for their university on only one Inclusive Digital Transformation Research Grant Seed Grant proposal. A person can be a PI or co-PI on only one active Afretec-funded research grant or seed grant at a time.</p> </li> </ul> <h1 id="grant-details">Grant details</h1> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Dates and Details</th> <th> </th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>Start Date</td> <td>June 1, 2024</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Award Period</td> <td>up to 12 months</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Disciplines</td> <td>Multi-institution collaborative Engineering and Technology research projects related to the inclusive digital transformation of Africa</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Maximum Award</td> <td>$50,000</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Estimated Awards</td> <td>It is expected that a total of 11 grants; up to 3 grants will be awarded per research cluster and up to 3 in other research areas depending on the quality of submissions and availability of funds.</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Submission Deadline</td> <td>Friday, January 26, 2024 at 17:00 Central African Time</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Submission Procedure</td> <td>Proposals are to be submitted via this <a href="https://cmu.infoready4.com/#viewApplicationForm/1925152">submission portal</a> by the above Submission Deadline.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Proposal - Seed Grants Inclusive Digital Transfromation of Africa]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CFP -AFRETEC Collaborative Research</title><link href="https://qiriro.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CFP -AFRETEC Collaborative Research"/><published>2023-12-14T20:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:11:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qiriro.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qiriro.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction-and-background">Introduction and Background</h1> <p>Carnegie Mellon University Africa (CMU-Africa), in support of Afretec, is launching a <a href="https://qiriro.github.io/assets/pdf/grants/afretec-large-grant - 2024-CFP.pdf">call for collaborative proposals</a> to enhance research capacity in the fields of engineering and technology, aiming to expedite and bolster the inclusive digital transformation of Africa. The research grants will support studies related to digital technologies, including artificial intelligence (AI), machine learning, information and communication technology, robotics, cybersecurity, and more. This initiative aligns with Afretec’s goal to foster inclusive digital growth on the African continent.</p> <h1 id="eligibility-criteria">Eligibility Criteria</h1> <ul> <li>Applicant teams must consist of Principal Investigator (PI) researchers from at least two Afretec member universities namely The American University in Cairo, Carnegie Mellon University, University of Lagos, University of Nairobi, University of Rwanda and the University of Witwatersrand.</li> <li>Additional PIs from non-Afretec African universities are eligible to be part of the application team and receive funding under this collaborative research grant. African universities include public or private institutions with headquarters in Africa and with a primary mission of education at the Bachelors, Masters, or Ph.D. level. Each applicant university must be accredited and locally recognized by prevailing law as an institution of higher education in the country of origin.</li> <li>Additional institutions that are not African universities can be engaged but cannot receive many resources through the seed grant.</li> <li>Each applicant university must provide a letter of intent signed by the authorized representative, declaring support for participation in the proposed research project and team.</li> <li>Each funded university will have a designated lead PI. The lead PI for each funded University is required to have a Ph.D. in a relevant discipline.</li> <li>A researcher can serve as a lead PI for their university on only one Inclusive Digital Transformation Research Grant proposal. A person can be a PI or co-PI on only one active Afretec-funded research grant or seed grant at a time.</li> </ul> <h1 id="grant-details">Grant details</h1> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Dates</th> <th> </th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>Start Date</td> <td>June 1, 2024</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Award Period</td> <td>up to 36 months</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Disciplines</td> <td>Multi-institution collaborative Engineering and Technology research projects related to the inclusive digital transformation of Africa</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Maximum Award</td> <td>$250,000</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Estimated Awards</td> <td>It is expected that up to 4 grants will be awarded depending on the quality of submissions and availability of funds.</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Submission Deadline</td> <td>Friday, January 26, 2024 at 17:00 Central African Time</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Submission Procedure</td> <td>Proposers must fill out an Expression of Interest form by January 16, 2024: <a href="https://forms.gle/bXg6zQHknp63qBdz9">Expression of Interest Form</a> Proposals are to be submitted via this <a href="https://cmu.infoready4.com/#viewApplicationForm/1924587">submission portal</a> by the above Submission Deadline.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Proposals - AFRETEC Inclusive Digital Transformation Collaborative Research]]></summary></entry></feed>